Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mr. Ryu, standby okay!
Good!
Amuro, standby for docking.
Ready?
I'm going in, Mr. Ryu!
5... 4...
3... 2... 1...
Laser searcher synchronized.
5... 4...
Gundam B Parts released!
Core Change! Docking, go!
After deserting the White Base...
...Amuro may never train like this again.
Meanwhile...
The battleship Gwazine
had departed from Granada...
...a Zeon frontline base on the moon.
It belonged to Rear Admiral Kycilia Zabi...
...eldest daughter of the Zabi family...
...and commander of Zeon's
Mobile Assault Force.
Kycilia was visiting M'Quve,
who supervised the mining of resources...
...which were considered vital
to both the Federation and Zeon forces.
The war effort had continued
regardless of the White Base's troubles.
Zeon's Secret Mine
What are we going to do
if Amuro comes back?
Well you know,
a deserter would certainly be executed.
No! You must be lying!
That's what military regulations dictate, but...
How can you think of doing that...
...to someone who's fought at your side?!
It just means we can do it if necessary.
Stop that, Sayla.
Come on, Fraw Bow.
Now I understand why Amuro left.
Why should I ask him to come back to this?
Look, Fraw Bow. Calm down.
We're not regular military here,
so we'd never do something like that.
But, Ryu...
...we can't continue to overlook
Amuro's selfish behavior.
Well, it's true that he's
behaving pretty badly
Don't you agree, Fraw Bow?
I understand that, but...
- Hey, take me along too!
- I want to go too!
No, you can't come. This isn't a joy ride.
Huh? Then what is it?
I'm going to look for Amuro.
You think she can convince him?
It's all a question of timing.
Do you think that big brother Amuro
is a V.S.O.P?
V.S.O.P?
Huh? Don't you know?
It means, 'very important person'.
Really?
Huh? Maybe I got it wrong.
I won't let them do anything foolish to Amuro.
I'll take responsibility.
I'll guarantee it, too.
You'll go and find him, won't you?
Amuro.
S-Sorry! I shouldn't have barged in like that.
Isn't this thing
what everyone's worried about?
That's not it!
They'll forgive you if you go back now.
Forgive me? For what?
Mr. Kai says deserters
are punishable by death.
So, that's how everyone really feels.
Leave!
You're wrong!
Everyone aboard the White Base
needs your strength!
Running away again?
The truth is that you're not confident
that everyone will accept you.
That's why you can't go back!
You can't possibly understand how I feel.
Amuro...!
Amuro!
How long do we have to sit here doing this?
We can't go anywhere
until Fraw Bow's back.
If we get moving again,
we can just tell her where we went.
Well, they say Central Asia
is neutral territory...
...but there're a lot of Zeon troops around.
What if they intercept our radio?
When Amuro gets back, I'm gonna...
I'm getting a metallic response at 2 o'clock.
What are you thinking,
stopping so suddenly?! It's dangerous!
She should just go back!
Who's that?
We get two grams in a ton.
This is a good quality Solium deposit,
just as expected.
If we can find five more deposits like this,
our forces will be able to...
It's not only about Solium.
The Federation must not get even
one gram of any precious resources.
This is what will lead us
to a decisive victory...
...and will also establish our control
after the war is over.
I'm aware of that.
There's another similar deposit
50 kilometers to the north.
I'll make sure you have all the men
and equipment you need.
I knew this was the Zeon mine!
I finally found it!
Hey! What's going on up there?!
Why won't you tell me anything?
Don't shout like that!
There's a Zeon mining base there!
What? Really?
No! What if they see you?!
How rude! I'm not that careless.
Wow! That's incredible!
We've gotta tell the White Base about this!
Wait! If the enemy hears our transmission,
we'll be at a disadvantage!
Then what are you going to do?
Fraw, you go back to the White Base
and tell them.
- What about you, Amuro?
- I'll stay here and continue observing.
All right.
3 hours!
Marker, any message?
Nothing yet.
I see.
If the enemy found us here,
we'd make an easy target.
We know. Don't take your eyes off
the sonar searcher.
Roger!
Any chance he's defected to Zeon?
No way!
Hey, it's possible.
They'd treat him like a hero
if he brings them the Gundam.
He is a deserter, after all.
Yeah...
What a pain in the butt.
This must be the Zeon mine...
General Revil plans to take on Odessa Day.
They don't have a single Zaku.
I can handle this!
If I take this place out with Gundam,
the Federation forces won't have to mobilize.
Mr. Bright and Ms. Mirai
won't mess around with me again!
What's going on?!
Lady Kycilia, this way!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
I've got to tell them, quickly!
If I'm spotted, I'll have to deal with it!
Prepare Adzam for launch at once!
M'Quve, I'm not sure if I can forgive you
for failing to detect that mobile suit.
My apologies, Lady Kycilia...
This is a good opportunity to test the Adzam.
I want you to do it.
Yes, Lady Kycilia. I certainly will.
Seeing the Federation's mobile suit
up close and in person...
...will be useful for our future strategy.
Why you...!
Behind me...
Is it over...?
What's this...?
Its performance seems far superior
to what Garma's data suggested.
M'Quve, approach it carefully.
Yes, ma'am.
It's above me!
I have the higher ground!
Launch the Leader!
Wh-What is this?!
Surface temperature, 4,000 degrees?!
Is it because of that sand-like stuff?!
Releasing 98% of all energy...
...for pilot and circuit protection.
98%?!
I won't be able to move!
A base near something that looks
like a mine? Are you sure?
Yes.
I don't like it.
It doesn't quite match the location...
...in the Federation estimates
which General Revil told us about.
We're not making this up! I saw it myself!
It's huge!
In any case, we can't just ignore it.
Let's go.
It's working, Lady Kycilia.
After all, we do have more experience...
...in mobile suit research.
The magnetic radiation field is weakening.
Finish him off quickly.
Roger that.
Offensive energy reduced.
I can move, then?
He deflected it!
A Zaku would have been crippled by now!
I'll try again!
Here I come!
Why you...!
Hurry! Shake him off!
Yes, ma'am!
You're not going to dump me!
It looks like this is it.
Destroy the base before our secrets get out!
But... But there are still soldiers there!
It doesn't matter!
Our state secrets are the priority now!
I understand.
The base... exploded...!
They abandoned... the base...
The Federation mobile suit...
Its performance is greater than rumored.
We will have to speed up
the deployment...
...of all the mobile suits we're testing.
I did it! I did it!
The Federation was gonna hit this Zeon base
with all of its force, and I destroyed it!
This one isn't any good, either.
All data systems have been
completely destroyed.
Ouch...!
"102nd Mining Base..."
This is the 102nd Mining Base?!
Does that mean what I destroyed
was just one...
...of many mining bases?!
So this isn't the mine that General Revil
is trying to take down?!
Is it a mine even bigger than this one?
Damn it!
Wh-Who are you?
Just someone passing by.
There should be a Federation or Zeon
rescue crew soon.
Yeah, right...
Just wait.
The bleeding's stopped.
This is a flare.
Please use it if you see help arrive.
Thanks. Think they'll come so soon?
A rescue...?
Of course they will.
You mustn't lose hope.
See you.
Hey.
Huh?
If you said you were
the pilot of that mobile suit...
...I'd find it hard to believe.
But if you are, don't go soft on your enemy.
You don't have enough lives for that.
Thanks.
Not enough lives, huh?
A flare!
Let's confirm. Approach it.
Fraw Bow...
Are you sure this is it?
Yes.
Wow...
Did the Gundam do all this on its own?
I can't think of any other possibilities.
But... this wasn't their main base.
You're right.
If it was, it wouldn't have fallen
with the Gundam alone.
He's caused quite a problem.
I think it's safe to say that,
because of the Gundam...
...the enemy will be on guard
and digging their heels in hard.
Amuro must think he's a hero
right about now.
But I can't see him anywhere.
He ran away!
Fraw!
What's his problem...?!
Who does Amuro think he is?!
He has no idea how I feel!
Amuro sees his foes up close.
Ral's troops are planning
an attack on the White Base.
When the Gundam's beam rifle
hits the Gouf...
...the enemy laughs.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Ramba Ral's Attack.
Next Time
Ramba Ral's Attack
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...